# **Eduardo Aragon**

## Software Engineer

Software engineer (BE-CS 2009) craving for disruptive software experiences that actually solve problems, learning every day and working hard to be a better person. With more than a decade of experience (9 years working remotely) helping startups, digital agencies, contract clients from around the world and enterprises in Colombia.



## Contact



## **Experience**

#### **Address**

Manizales, Colombia, 170003

#### **Phone**

311-307-2880

#### E-mail

earagon87@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/earagon87/



Java	••••• Excellent
Node.js	••••• Excellent
Rest Apis	●●●● Excellent
AWS	●●●○ Very Good
Docker	●●●○○ Good

### 2021-06 -Current

2020-12 -

2015-03 -

2020-11

2021-04

#### **Senior Backend Developer**

EPAM, Remote

- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.

## **Senior Engineer**

Southworks, Remote

 Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.

### **Software Developer**

IguanaIT, Remote

- Collaborated on all stages of systems development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality and function prior to release.

#### 2015-02 Software Engineer

Devfactory, Remote

- Authored code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Conducted regression testing, analyzed results and submitted observations to development team.

# 2013-01 - Java Developer

2013-05 Webdatacast, Remote

- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Adjusted design parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.

# 2012-04 - Projects Engineer

2013-01 Nexura, Cali, Valle

# 2010-06 - Senior Analyst

2012-04

Newshore, Manizales, Caldas

- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Introduced agile methodologies and effective development best practices to division to enhance product development.

# **Education**

# 2004-08 - Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science

Universidad Del Valle - Cali, Colombia